Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> And God speak all these words saying,
I'm the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt out of the
house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me.
Thou shall not make unto thee any graven
image or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above or that is in the
earth beneath or that is in the water
under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me. And showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy.
Six days shall thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother that thy
days may be long upon the land which the
Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shall not kill. Thou shall not
commit adultery. Thou shall not steal.
Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
covet thy neighbor's house, thou shall
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbor's. I read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So, we like to say that here on question
and answer, you can ask us a question
and we'll answer it according to the
King James Bible. And if we cannot find
the answer, we will seek further counsel
to bring you an answer at a later time.
The questions we will not answer are the
vague and the long scripture questions
and questions of debate. We are not here
to debate, we're here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But, let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got brother
Jerome.
>> Peace. Peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> You're on mute.
>> Good evening, everybody.
>> Brother James.
>> Good evening, everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
Brother Shawn.
>> Good evening.
>> And we have the guest caller with us,
and I'm brother Cornell.
Sister Deborah, what is our first
question of the evening?
>> All right, can you hear me?
>> Now, you we hear you loud and clear. Go
right ahead with our first question of
the evening.
>> Okay, there are several held-over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Uh so, my colleague says,
"I have a female friend going through
issues with her husband concerning
paying tithes. Her dilemma is obeying
her husband and saving money or serving
God by paying tithes. Can you provide
advice?"
>> All right, advice on this paying tithes
and um what should be done with that
Brother Jerome?
>> Um you you know your your marital
situation.
You know, I I don't know what your
marital situation is.
But um in Acts the fifth chapter, it
kind of gives an example of a wife that
uh obeyed her husband
to do something that's contrary to the
word of God. And and and I'll read that
to you, okay? So, let's go to Acts the
fifth chapter.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
one.
And you can read it to the 10, uh
Brother James.
>> Okay.
Acts 5 and verse 1 says, "But a certain
man named Ananias with Sapphira his wife
sold a possession
and kept back part of the price, his
wife also being privy to it and brought
a certain part and laid it at the
apostles' feet.
But Satan said Ananias I'm sorry, but
Peter said Ananias, "Why has Satan
filled thine heart to lie to the Holy
Ghost and to keep back part of the price
of the land?
Whilst it remained, was it not thine
own? And after it was sold, was it not
in thine own power? Why has thou
conceived this thing in thine heart?
Thou has not lied unto men, but unto
God.
>> Mhm.
>> And Ananias hearing these words fell
down and gave up the ghost. And great
fear came on all of them that heard
these things. And the young men arose,
wound him up and carried him out and
buried him. And it was about
>> The husband, he had done contrary to the
word of God, you know.
And now, the next thing we're going to
read is how to
wife going to re-
going to react. What is she going to do?
Is she going to do the same thing that
the husband did concerning this
situation?
Okay? So, go ahead, keep read.
>> And it was about the space of three
hours after, when his wife, not knowing
what was done, came in.
And Peter answered unto her, "Tell me
whether you sold the land for so much."
And she said, "Yea, for so much." Then
Peter said unto her, "How is it that you
have agreed together to tempt the spirit
of the Lord? Behold, the feet of them
which have buried thine husband are at
the door and shall carry thee out."
Then fell she down straightway at his
feet and yielded up the ghost. And the
young men came in and found her dead and
they carried her forth, buried her by
her husband.
>> Yeah, so when it come to
you being a servant of the Lord, I know
the man is the head of the house, but
when he
want you to do things contrary to the
word of God, follow God.
That's all I got.
>> Yeah. Hey, brother Jerome, you mind if
we read that Malachi 3?
>> You can go ahead.
>> Yeah, Malachi 3 and and that verse 8
through 10.
>> Uh-huh.
>> When you get there, brother Jane.
>> Malachi 3:8-10
says, "Will a man rob God?
Yet ye have robbed me.
But ye say, 'Wherein have we robbed
thee?' In tithes and offerings.
Ye are cursed with a curse, for ye have
robbed me, even this whole nation."
>> It's the Lord speaking. Go ahead.
>> "Bring ye all the tithes into the
storehouse, that there may be meat in
the in mine house. And prove me now
herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I
will not open you the windows of heaven,
and pour you out a blessing, that there
shall not be room enough to receive it."
>> A virgin womb, it's a blessing in paying
them tithes too, ain't it?
The word of God.
>> Yes, sir. Cuz thus says the Lord.
>> All right, brother.
>> Thank you for letting me add that in.
We hope that that answered your question
as we uh move on to our next one.
>> All right, next one. Tandula De Jesus
says, "I have a question pertaining to
the Lord's dietary law. I am aware of
clean meats. My concern is cheese. If a
person
goes to a drive-thru,
you should not get cheese on a burger or
order a pizza due to unclean, right?"
>> Well, we we can't say that. I mean, when
you go through a drive-thru or if you
getting you some pizza, uh I advise to
you is inquire and do your research.
Find out what type of cheese they use
and whether or not it uh
is clean according to the dietary law
because sometimes they mix in some
animals that may not be clean in their
cheese, but you would have to do your
own
research and uh
hey, always feel free after you have
researched to bring your own cheese to
the party.
If need be.
So, once you are approving that to be,
you know, clean cheese, then
you good to go. That's all I got.
All right. We're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one, Steve Googers asks, in Job
40:15,
what is Behemoth?
Is this an animal that was around in
Job's time? And is it around today?
>> All right, brother Julius. What is
Behemoth? Sounds big. What do you say,
brother?
>> Sounds like uh
let's go to Job 40.
Cuz I I really researched this matter
for a long for some years, man.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
Because if it if the book mentions them,
he's here. Let's see when he got here.
Because some people want to go back and
say this is the woolly mammoth and this
is prehistoric uh dinosaurs. No, it's
not.
Do you know how I know?
Job 40
and read verse 15, James.
>> Behold now Behemoth, which I made with
thee. He eateth grass as an ox.
>> He eat He eat grass like an ox. He said,
I made Behemoth with you. Man was
created on the sixth day. If you go back
to Genesis
uh 1:24,
man was made on the sixth day and so
were the beasts of the field.
So, that means that it is here in our
creation.
Behold now Behemoth, which I made with
thee. He eateth grass like an ox.
Go ahead.
>> Lo, now his strength is in his loins,
and his force is in the navel of his
belly.
>> Go ahead.
>> He moveth his tail like a cedar. The
sinews of his stones are wrapped
together.
>> That is the muscles and the ligaments.
He is a muscular animal. Go ahead.
>> His bones are as strong pieces of brass.
His bones are like bars of iron.
>> Skip down to verse 23. Go ahead.
>> Behold, he drinketh up a river and
hasteth not. He trusteth that he can
draw up Jordan into his mouth.
>> So, he drinks a lot of water. He is a
land-based and he's a water-based
creature. If you read the previous
verse, uh at verse 22, he drink a lot of
water and he eat a lot of grass.
hippopotamus
>> Oh, okay.
>> hippopotamus
>> All right.
And thank you for that, brother. And we
hope that that um answered uh
brother Stephen's question as we
continue to move on to our next.
>> Moving on. Uh
Pam Banks asks, "How do you stop them
from speaking against the word of God
out of ignorance? Strong Sunday
believers are hard to tolerate. Walk
away?"
>> All right. So, you got people speaking
against the word of God. Um what do you
do in that situation if you're not
getting across? Do you just walk away,
brother Julius?
>> The word of God can stop them. It's not
you that's stopping them. It's the word
of God. So, the first thing you have to
ask people is
um
because they are strong in their faith
like we all profess to be. But,
uh
uh let's go uh James, let's go to
uh let's go to 1 Thes-
I think I want 1 Thessalonians chapter
5.
Let me see here.
Cuz you got to prove all things. Let's
go to 2 Timothy first. 2 Timothy chapter
16.
Uh
You know, the you supposed to preach the
gospel, but if somebody don't agree,
then you walk away. But, if they want to
challenge your mark, you have to it's
your job to make them prove their
ministry.
Ask them the origin of Sunday and who
changed the Sabbath day from Saturday to
Sunday.
2 Timothy 3 and 16. What the book say?
>> All scripture is given by inspiration of
God.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And is profitable for doctrine, for
reproof, for correction, for instruction
in righteousness.
>> Verse 17.
>> That the man of God may be perfect,
thoroughly furnished unto all good
works.
>> Now, uh
I want also thank you 1 Thessalonians
chapter 5.
>> Okay.
>> 1 Thessalonians chapter 5 and I got one
verse.
>> Okay.
>> 1 Thessalonians 5 and verse 21.
See, because if you profess a faith, if
you're going to profess a strong faith,
you should be able to be able to be able
to defend your faith.
Verse 21. Go ahead, brother.
>> Prove all things.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hold fast that which is good.
>> Now, whether they will hear or whether
they will not.
If they won't if they will hear and make
a correction, then you go there. That's
good. If they won't, then you walk away.
Don't cast your pearl before swine.
That's all I got.
>> Well, I have a I have one
I have one thing I see.
I have one thing I see the people they
run with this strong Sunday
believe in Christ.
I ask him, "Do
uh uh
Do you believe
Bible was written in it?" Yeah.
Okay, then.
What you say is the word of God. Do it
to me in the Bible.
>> There you go.
>> And that's the end of the story.
Yeah.
But if you can't show it,
then you say you need to learn some
more.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question there as we continue to
push on.
>> Moving on. I care Michael asks, "In
Exodus 20:10,
can serving the congregation by making
their place as they stand in line on the
Sabbath day be considered as work?"
>> All right. Exodus 20:10,
Brother James, you read that earlier,
but read that verse 10 and the guest
caller will take it from there. Is that
considered as work?
>> Okay. Exodus 20:10 says, "But the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God.
In it, thou shall not do any work. Thou,
nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates."
>> So, when it come to that,
it depends on what you're doing on the
Sabbath uh of why you're serving this on
the Sabbath day.
You know, uh if they're taking care of
the Lord's business,
it's not against
the word of God. Let me show you
something about the feast. We're going
to read go and read one verse.
And
and we're going to go one other place
after this. Let's go into Exodus the
12th chapter and read verse 16.
>> Okay.
Exodus 12 and verse 16 says,
"And in the first day there shall be a
holy convocation. And in the seventh day
there shall be a holy convocation to
you.
No manner of work shall be done in them
save that which every man must eat that
only may be done of you."
>> You know, so they said
So this food is being given to people on
the Lord's Sabbath day and it could be
the Lord's feast days.
As long as you taking care of the Lord's
business. Let's go into Matthew the 12th
chapter and read verse five.
>> Okay.
Matthew
Matthew 12 and verse five says,
"Or have you not read in the law have
that on the Sabbath days the priests in
the temple profane the Sabbath and are
blameless?"
>> So that's the whole thing. If you taking
care of the Lord's business by serving
that food and people lined up to get
against it or to get it, that's the
Lord's business.
So
So the Lord don't the Lord hold you
blameless just like he did the priests.
He told them not to kindle a fire on the
Sabbath but they still they had to do
the evening and the morning oblations.
Those were
sacrifices by fire.
So they had to kindle a fire, but they
was taking care of the Lord's business.
That is what's important.
So yes, they don't So So
that kind of work is permissible.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Well, hope that that answered your
question as we continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Jade Enduring asks, "What to
do if your grandparents are pastors and
have rejected the truth, but still wants
you to come hang out?"
>> All right. So, you got grandparents that
are pastors and they don't want to hear
the truth, but they still want you to
come and hang out with them. Brother
Julius.
>> It depend on what you hanging out doing
with them. They are still your grand-
They still your grandparents and you
honor them like you honor your mother
and your father, but they still your
grand-
your grandparents. You don't have to
deal with them with the word of God. You
could learn how to do with that. Here's
the answer right here. Let's go to
Romans the 12th chapter.
You
know the word of God. You have to lead
by example in spite of them. You lead
You live your life serving God.
Romans 12
and give me verse one verse.
Verse 18.
>> Well, Romans 12 and 18 says, "If it be
possible, as much as lieth in you, live
peaceably with all men."
>> And that includes your grandparents. And
you can do it. You can maneuver around
it.
You know?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. You can do with That's all I got.
You can do with You can You can honor
them and respect them. You don't have to
deal with them with the book, but you
lead by example.
>> That's right.
>> You respect them, honor them, and live
peaceably with them as much as live
within you.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. That's it. Let your light shine,
Jade.
All right.
Hope that answered your question. We
going to move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Yeah, Isha Israel asked, "What
does the Bible say about a spouse that
constantly masturbates?
I have told him it's not something that
should be going on, but he continues to
do it. Are there any scriptures on this
subject?"
>> All right, so we got a spouse and um is
there any scriptures
on the subject of this sentence here?
Yes, caller.
>> Well, when you say scriptures,
I don't I haven't seen any
uh that's contrary to it or promote it.
I don't think it's right, but I have but
I don't have the but I don't know of any
scripture that promotes it
or condemns it.
Anybody else have a scripture they can
read?
If you can educate me, too. But, I have
not seen anything against it, so I can't
give you something that is not written.
>> Yeah.
>> Pray and give them pray and actually ask
them to give them a
a mind to change their behavior.
That's it.
>> Yeah.
>> That's it.
>> Yeah. That's it. Yeah. Pray.
And uh
we're going to leave it there.
And we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Jade Enduring asked, "Does the
Lord give us signs to get our attention,
such as a car crash?"
>> All right, so do the Lord sometimes give
you signs to get your attention, car
crash being one of them? Brother Julius,
we know there's others. What say you?
>> The Lord uh comes to us by way of like
the book say, by dreams,
uh Uh, mostly by his word. Do you read
the book? And uh uh
Uh,
he come to you by dream.
And he come to you
with the warning. Let's uh let's go to
Ezekiel the 33rd chapter. Here's one
right here.
It's it's very very possible.
Sometimes he use put you he make you
sick put you on your sick bed to correct
you.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah.
33?
And begin at verse one, James.
>> Okay.
>> But he always give you warnings.
Will you get it go ahead, brother.
>> Ezekiel 33:1 says, "Again, the word of
the Lord came unto me saying,
'Son of man, speak to the children of
thy people and say unto them, "When I
bring the sword upon a land, if the
people of the land take a man of their
coast and set him for their watchman.
If when he seeth the sword come upon the
land, he blow the trumpet and warn the
people.
Then whosoever heareth the sound of the
trumpet and taketh not warning, if the
sword come and take him away, his blood
shall be upon his own head.
>> Uh-huh.
>> He heard the sound of the trumpet and
took not warning.
His blood shall be upon him.
But he that taketh warning shall deliver
his soul.'"
>> So now, the Lord always always give you
warning. Something that possibly
preludes something that's about to
happen, but he gives you warning. My
last place, Job the 33rd chapter.
Job 33.
Time and chance happens to everybody.
But if we are disobedient, then he can
testify those things.
Job 33 and we going to read verse 14
to 17.
>> Okay.
>> Job 33:14-17.
Go ahead, James.
>> For God speaketh once, yea, twice, yet
man perceiveth not.
>> Uh-huh.
>> In a dream, in a vision of the night,
when deep sleep falleth upon men, in
slumberings upon the bed.
>> Sometimes cuz you in your bed or in your
sleep. Go ahead.
>> Then he openeth the ears of men, and
sealeth their instruction.
>> Uh-huh.
>> That That he may withdraw man from his
purpose, and hide pride from man.
>> That's the best we can do with that
right now. That's the best I got,
Cornell. Anybody else?
>> Let me do something.
>> Yes, caller.
>> You know,
read the question of that but
like
uh uh car crash. You know,
uh uh
think it was a tower fell on some people
and killed them.
>> That was the tower of Siloam.
>> You know, I want you to go and read what
Jesus said about the that that like
either tower or wall fell on these
people. See what he said.
>> All right.
>> Pull it up right quick.
>> Yeah. Search mode.
>> That's Luke the 13th chapter.
Luke chapter 13, James.
>> Okay.
>> Answer around that verse uh
Think around four.
>> Okay.
Um yeah. Yes, it is. Uh
Luke 13:4,
let me see here.
Uh yes, Luke 13 and
>> Pick it up at verse two.
>> Okay.
Luke 13:2
says, "And Jesus answering said unto
them, "Suppose ye that these Galileans
were sinners above all the Galileans,
because they suffered such things?
I tell you, nay: but except ye repent,
ye shall all likewise perish.
>> Continue.
>> Or
Or those 18 upon whom the tower of
Siloam fell, and slew them.
Think ye that they were sinners above
all men that dwelt in Jerusalem?
I tell you, nay: but except ye repent,
ye shall all likewise perish.
>> Yes, caller.
>> But the whole thing is, sometimes you
see that say they know more than nobody
else. But there's another scripture
would tell you sometimes it's about
chance.
>> Yep.
>> There's another place. I I I can't
remember where it is, but it say, you
know, that there's that that chance,
because he was a
This happened to be in
daytime.
That's all I have to say.
But there's other scripture that that
clearly admit, but I I can't
find it right now.
>> Ecclesiastes 9.
>> Okay. What does it say?
>> Ecclesiastes 9, James, and
I think verse 11. Directly.
>> Okay. Ecclesiastes 9:11 says, "I
returned, and saw under the sun, that
the race is not to the swift, nor the
battle to the strong, neither yet bread
to the wise, nor yet riches to men of
understanding, nor yet favor to men of
skill, but time and chance happeneth to
them all."
>> So, when you have a car accident, don't
mean that you sinned against God.
It could be time and chance.
>> Yes, sir.
>> might be in the wrong
at the wrong time.
That's all I have to say.
>> And hook that verse 12 up with that
and and that's that's what Yes, caller
is talking about.
>> Verse 12 says, "For man also knoweth not
his time, as the fishes that are taken
in an evil net, and as the birds that
are caught in the snare, so are the sons
of men snared in an evil time, when it
falleth suddenly upon them."
>> Yeah.
It could have just It could have just It
could have just been
just bad timing. And it don't
necessarily didn't even have to
necessarily be your fault.
>> That's it.
And the Lord don't have to be warning
you about nothing.
>> Thank you.
You muted, Connie.
>> All right, my apologies. Um
we hope that that answered your question
as we continue to move on to our next
one.
>> Next one, Connie Lee says, "My spouse
brought some of those long
cylinder-shaped
candles that have a fake Jesus on them,
but he got the plain ones. He was told
that those candles attach unwanted
spirits. Is that true?"
>> Well, you don't have to have a a candle
to have some unwanted spirits around
because
the earth is filled with them.
But when they're talking about this this
candle, this elongated candle, it looks
something like that.
And those are the candles that they
burn. And you see you notice it got the
little heart in the um
in the middle of the chest. And the
sacred heart, they call that the sacred
heart,
is one of the most widely practiced and
well-known Catholic devotions. It
symbolizes the long-suffering love and
compassion of the heart of Christ
towards humanity. And that's where they
got that from. And also you notice on
that candle is an image. And the Lord
talks to us about images. Let's go into
that Deuteronomy the fourth chapter,
brother James. Deuteronomy 4.
Because even if you get the plain one, I
mean, once you come into the knowledge
of God, why even purchase a candle that
has an image on it and you know what it
stands for, no matter how sweet it may
smell.
Deuteronomy 4.
And let's pick it up at that verse 11
and let's see what the Lord said about
any type of images, which which that was
what I just showed.
Deuteronomy 4 and 11, brother. Go ahead.
>> And ye came near and stood under the
mount.
And the mount burned with fire unto the
midst of heaven, with darkness, clouds,
and thick darkness.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And the Lord spake unto you out of the
midst of the fire. Ye heard the voice of
the words, but saw no similitude. Only
ye heard a voice.
>> So, if you heard the words, but you
didn't see no similitude, you didn't see
no shape, you didn't see nothing of what
the Lord looked like. Verse 13.
>> And he declared unto you his covenant,
which he commanded you to perform, even
the ten commandments. And he wrote them
upon two tables of stone.
>> Uh-huh. Skip down, brother, to that
verse 15.
>> Take ye therefore good heed unto
yourselves
for ye saw no manner of similitude on
the day that the Lord spake unto you in
Horeb out of the midst of the fire.
>> Yes, one more verse.
>> Lest ye corrupt yourselves and make your
graven image the similitude of any
figure, the likeness of male or female.
>> All right, and this is a graven image
and it is in the likeness of a man. And
the Lord say, "Don't do that."
So, that's um not wise to do according
to the word of God and hey,
get you another candle that may smell
good. That's all I got. Anybody else?
>> Well, well, the person said that he got
the plain one with nothing on it. You
understand?
>> Oh.
Yeah.
>> As long as as long as there ain't no
image or nothing on it, there ain't
nothing but a candle.
>> That's right.
>> And and the candle and candles don't
bring on
unwanted spirits.
What bring unwanted spirits is
misbehaving.
>> Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
>> All right.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
So, we hope that that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next one.
>> Our next one, Yoself asked, "Why is the
brazen serpent being used by Jesus as a
reference to himself when in 2 Kings
18:4,
this was used as an idol and destroyed?"
>> All right, why is the brazen serpent
being used
by Jesus as a reference to himself? Then
that 2 Kings 18:4, brother Julius.
>> Let's Let's Let's Let's break this down
and get to the bottom of this brazen
serpent. Because the Lord don't promote
idolatry.
>> Right.
>> He don't promote idolatry. Read verse uh
Uh pick it up at Let's start this at
verse three. This is Hezekiah. What
Heze- King Hezekiah did. Go ahead.
>> And he did that which was right in the
sight of the Lord according to all that
David his father did.
>> What did he do?
>> He removed the high places and break the
images and cut down the groves and break
in pieces the brazen serpent that Moses
had made.
For unto those days the children of
Israel did burn incense to it and he
called it Nehush tan.
>> And what else did he do?
>> He trusted in the Lord God of Israel so
that after him was none like him among
all the kings of Judah nor any that were
before him.
>> Now, he He trusted the Lord. He believed
in the God of Israel. He removed all
those things because Israel would
end up worshipping that thing which
would really have tested their faith.
Let's look at Numbers the 21st chapter.
>> Mhm. I'm there.
>> Just bear with me real quick. Numbers
21. Numbers 21, this is what we got to
understand about these things. Numbers
21, let's read verse five. Starting at
verse five. Go ahead.
>> Numbers 20 21 and five.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And the people spake against God and
against Moses. Wherefore have you
brought us up out of Egypt to die in the
wilderness?
For there is no bread, neither is there
any water, and our soul loatheth this
light bread.
>> God just brought them out of Egypt and
provided them food, water
uh and uh and and everything that they
needed in the wilderness and they still
complaining. Continue verse six.
>> And the Lord sent fiery serpents among
the people.
And they bit the people, and much people
of Israel died.
>> Continue James, a little bit faster.
>> Therefore, the people came to Moses and
said, "We have sinned, for we have
spoken against the Lord and against
thee. Pray unto the Lord that he take
away the serpents from us." And Moses
prayed for the people.
>> Now, these the Lord sent these serpents
and they bit some and they killed some
of the people. Go ahead, verse eight.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "Make thee
a fiery serpent and set it upon a pole.
And it shall come to pass that everyone
that is bitten, when he looketh upon it,
shall live."
>> So, this was set up for act of faith.
They would fail. Now, I'mma make you
prove your faith. Go ahead.
>> And Moses made a serpent of brass and
put it upon a pole. And it came to pass
that if a serpent had bitten any man,
when he beheld the serpent of brass, he
lived.
>> Because it was a test of their faith.
Look up on it, you live. You get healed.
It's always been about faith. One more
Let's go to John, the eighth chapter.
Saint John.
Saint John, the eighth chapter.
And that's the problem from there from
then to now, we have no faith. John
eight, read verse 19. John eight and
verse 19, James. Go ahead and read.
>> Then said they unto him, "Where is thy
father?" Jesus answered, "Ye neither
know me nor my father. If ye had known
me,
>> Skip down. Skip down, James, to verse
23.
>> And he said unto
"Ye are from beneath. I am from above.
Ye are of this world, I am not of this
world."
>> Skip all the way down uh uh uh uh uh uh
uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh
uh uh
Uh I'm sorry, verse 24. That's what I
really want. Go ahead.
>> "I said therefore unto you, that ye
shall die in your sins. For if ye
believe not that I am he, ye shall die
in your sins."
>> So now, what happened at verse 30 and
31? We're done.
>> Then said Jesus to those Jews which
believed on him.
>> To the ones that believed on him. Yes.
>> "If ye continue in my word, then are ye
my disciples indeed."
>> So now,
it's all about faith, sisters and
brothers. It's all about faith.
Go back and read St. John the third
chapter. He mentioned the fiery serpent
again. But, it's all about faith. Not a
instrument to be worshipped. It's just
what what is really did. It is about
faith. That's what the brazen serpent
was set up for. And then Hezekiah came
and tore it down and showed the people
to believe and trust in God. That's what
this is all about.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, absolutely. James, read that verse
32.
>> "And ye shall know the truth, and the
truth shall make you free."
>> Amen. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. All right.
Yes, caller.
>> That's why Jesus referred to the
serpent. He is just like the word when
the serpent when the son of man is
is risen. Did you read that? Then he
going to bring and then the people will
come to him. What is that in St. John?
>> The third chapter.
>> And read the and read the verses. See
what it say.
>> St. John the third chapter, uh James,
and let's pick this up.
Uh and pick it up at uh
verse 14.
>> Okay.
It says,
"And as Moses lifted up the serpent in
the wilderness, even so must the Son of
Man be lifted up."
>> So now but he told you verse 12. If we
verse 12 James, we need to read this. Go
ahead.
>> "If I have told you earthly things and
you believe not, how shall you believe
if I tell you of heavenly things?"
>> It's always been about faith and belief.
Verse 14 now.
>> "And as Moses lifted up the serpent in
the wilderness, even so must the Son of
Man be lifted up."
>> So we got to believe on him. We have to
believe on him. And verse 18.
>> "He that believeth on him is not
condemned, but he that believeth not is
condemned already because he had not
believed in the name of the only
begotten Son of God."
>> So you have to come to him. He's the
door and you got to believe him and obey
him and keep his commandments. That's
what it's all about. It's what it's
always been about.
Yes, call
>> reason it came destroyed it because the
people made a god out of it.
>> Oh, they did. They started worshipping
the serpent.
>> All it was similar faith. If you don't
want to die from a snake bite, look at
the snake on the stick.
Yeah. If you didn't believe that Moses,
then you didn't look at the snake. When
you got bit, you died.
The same thing with Jesus. Jesus said
when he get lifted up, everybody going
to come to him. The one that believe on
him, they going to live.
And the one that don't believe on him is
going to die. Just like it was in the
wilderness.
>> Yes, sir.
>> the people start god out of it and start
worshipping it, then it became a pagan
symbol.
Jesus didn't set it up as a pagan
symbol. He set it up as a proof a proof
as proof of your faith.
>> That's all I got to say.
>> Mhm. All right.
Good add on there, guest caller. We hope
that that answered your question as we
move on to our next question.
>> Uh next question.
Uh Troy Barbara asks, "Is there any
place in the Bible which shows that God
knows exactly when someone will die? For
example, when you're born, God know this
person will live until 10 years old or
20, etc., then die?"
>> All right. Is there somewhere in the
scriptures where Jerome with that to uh
shows that God knows a exactly
your check out time,
10, 20, or baby?
>> Uh if you understand that
God is the one that has given us the
breath of life, which is the air we
breathe,
>> Yeah.
>> he the one that give us the air that we
breathe, which is called the breath of
life.
He can take that breath of life, too.
And when he take it, okay, he he know
when he going to take it. And he know
how old you going to be when he decide
to take it.
Okay? So, let's go to
um
Job
12th chapter. Let's read verse 9 and 10.
We going to go to Psalms after that.
Psalms 146 after that.
>> Okay.
>> James, Job the 12th chapter
verse 9 and 10.
>> Okay. Job the 12th chapter verse 9 and
10 says,
"Who knoweth not in all these that the
hand of the Lord has wrought this?
>> Mhm.
>> In whose hand is the soul of every
living thing and the breath of all
mankind?"
>> Yes, so he the one gave us the air that
we breathing. And when he decided to
take it, he know how old you going to be
when he take it.
>> Okay.
Uh go to Psalms 146 and read verse two,
and then we going to skip.
>> Okay. Psalms 146 and verse two says,
"While I live, will I praise the Lord. I
will sing praises unto my God while I
have any being."
>> I'm alive. Verse four.
>> His breath goeth forth, he return to the
his earth, and that very day his
thoughts perish.
>> Yeah, and the Lord know how old you are
when that happen. Okay.
Um
one more place. Let's go to uh Luke
chapter 12. This about a rich man.
When the Lord uh when he was boasting
about all his riches and the barns where
he was going to put all his riches and
stuff in or whatever. And the Lord said,
"Thou fool."
>> Yep.
>> 12 verse 16 read to the 20.
>> Okay. Luke 12 and verse 16 says,
"And he spake a parable unto them
saying, The ground of a certain rich man
brought forth plentifully.
And he thought within himself saying,
What shall I do because I have no room
where to bestow my fruits. And he said,
This will I do. I will pull down my
barns and build greater. And there will
I bestow all my fruits and my goods. And
I will say to my soul, Soul, thou has
much goods laid up for many years. Take
thine ease, eat, drink, and be merry.
But God said unto him, Thou fool. This
night thy soul shall be required of
thee.
Then who shall those things be which
thou has provided.
>> I mean, the Lord said this night he was
going to kill him, and
the way you kill a man easily is take
that breath. You can You can shoot him
and everything, but he can still be
breathing, but you take that breath,
that's it.
>> Yep.
>> You
know,
>> right, brother. Lord said that breath
returns to him who gave it.
>> I guess called him.
>> Yes, sir. Guess called him.
>> All sound good, but go ahead and read
what the Lord said about honoring your
mother and your father.
Fourth commandment.
>> Okay.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That your days may be long.
>> It said It says in Exodus In Exodus 20
and 12, "Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee."
>> Now, what if you don't honor?
Then your days won't be long.
Is that right?
>> Yeah.
>> Now, Jesus
Now, when Jesus got ready to go up to a
feast,
his own brothers didn't believe in him.
I think it's in St. John somewhere.
But then they told him to go up to the
feast cuz they knew the Jews wanted to
kill him.
He said, "Look, I know my time." But
what he said about them? Can somebody
find it right quick?
>> All right. Search mode.
Still searching.
>> St. John 7.
>> Okay.
>> St. John 7 around 6, James.
Uh St. John 7:6 says, "Then Jesus said
unto them, 'My time is not yet come, but
your time is alway ready."
The world cannot hate Mhm.
>> So, if your time is always ready, that
means you can die any day.
I would say I would be careful about
saying that God knew
the
when everybody's going to die.
I say that's some very That's a very
very
I say
errish statement.
And he knew when you born, he knew the
exact day you going to die. Maybe ain't
doing all of that. Cuz maybe the Lord
can leave some things
uh uh uh
open to your behavior.
If you a sinner
and you keep doing crazy things,
then you can cut your days short. If you
serve God
and you do what he say,
then you can lengthen your days.
But they never say it. Now, it never say
it point-blank in the Bible that God
knew when exactly when you going to die.
He knew when that guy was going to die.
And individuals, he knew it because they
are doing certain things and they
announce it. But to say everybody,
I'd be real careful about that. That's
all I have to say.
>> He gave Hezekiah Did he give Hezekiah 15
more years?
>> That's what he did. He had told him he
was going to die, but Hezekiah turned
and prayed.
>> Yeah.
>> And then he
added 4 years to his life.
So, like I say, I'd be careful about
making that statement that God knew when
exactly when you going to die.
Not that he can't know it, cuz he is the
one that gave you life. I don't care for
You got conditions. Like I say, I said
before, you good and evil,
life and death. choose life and live.
Okay?
>> Yeah.
All right.
>> Go ahead.
>> We're going to leave it right there,
sister, as we do a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:22.
Uh Bulldog says,
"If the wife committed adultery and the
husband lay with her, could he still
divorce her later after trying to make
the marriage work?"
>> All right.
Wife committed adultery can and he laid
with her, can he still divorce her later
if the marriage is not working? Guest
caller.
>> No.
Cuz once he laid with her,
that negated it.
He'll be in guilty because that is an
act of forgiveness. So, if you forgive
somebody, you can't later on take your
forgiveness back.
He had to commit adultery again.
But until it happen,
you stuck with a partner.
That's all he got to say.
>> All right, sister Deborah. New
territory?
>> Uh yes, new territory.
Uh we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday,
May the 6th, 2026.
And Shaquala Akul Joby asks,
he says, "I get that
on judgment day, everyone
who's dead will rise.
But what about those who died in
abnormal ways and didn't have any
physical body left? How exactly are
those people supposed to rise?"
>> All right. Well,
being that the Lord formed man out of
the dust of the ground,
no matter what your demise may have
been, the Lord will
have the power to put it all back
together like he did when he first
created man.
So, whether you was
eaten by animals or
on the bottom of the sea, whatever your
demise may have been, the Lord is
powerful enough to put everything back
together cuz he say everybody got to
stand before the judgment seat of
Christ. So, no one escapes. Open to the
path.
>> Revelation 20.
That's what I said. Go read it.
>> Yeah, brother.
>> Revelation 20.
>> Yeah.
>> In verse 12.
>> Mhm.
>> It says, "And I saw the dead, small and
great, stand before God. And the books
were opened, and another book was
opened, which is the book of life. And
the dead were judged out of those things
which were written in the books
according to their works."
>> This is the great white throne judgment.
Go ahead.
>> "And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it. And death and hell delivered up
the dead which were in them. And they
were judged every man according to their
works."
>> So, now, you got all these deteriorated
bodies, all these bodies that have been
in the grave for all these thousands of
years.
Is anything too hard for God?
>> No.
>> If he can make a man out of the dirt,
is anything too hard for God?
>> No.
No.
>> Yes, call it.
>> Well, the whole thing he said, "Dust
thou art, and to dust thou shall
return." He didn't tell you how you were
going to return to the dust.
>> Mhm.
>> And when you go into Daniel the 12th
chapter, it said, "Those that sleep
in the dust shall rise."
>> Yes, sir.
>> I don't care how you got there, whether
you burned and end up there, whether you
drowned and end up there, or whether
alligator ate you and defecated you on
the ground, you still get back to the
dust.
>> That's right.
>> The Lord formed me out of the
And the Lord God formed man out of the
dust of the ground. If he did it once,
he can do it again. That's all I have to
say.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right.
>> We hope that answered your question.
Question pertaining to that judgment day
as we move on.
>> Okay, moving on. Norman Nick says, "I'm
trying to understand Isaiah 34:16.
No one of these shall fail. None shall
want her mate. Can you clear this up,
please?"
>> Right. Let's let's go there to that
Isaiah 34, James.
And I believe verse 16.
Isaiah 34 and 16.
>> Mhm.
Yes.
>> Talked about seeking out of the
out of the book of the Lord, but let's
read it, brother, and uh
have Deborah repeat the question and see
what is the correlation between the two.
Go ahead.
>> It says, "Seek ye out the book of the
Lord and read.
No one of those one No one of these
shall fail. None shall want her mate.
For my mouth it has commanded and his
spirit it has gathered them."
>> Open to the panel. Deborah, what's the
question again?
>> The question is, he wants understanding
on that scripture, "No one of these
shall fail. No
None shall want her mate." So, he wants
this to be cleared up.
>> It says, "Seek ye out of the book of the
Lord," didn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> And the book of the Lord.
>> Mhm.
>> And read
it. It is word he's talking about. His
word is not going to
>> That's right.
If you keep his word and walk in it, you
ain't going to fail either, right guest
caller?
>> It's all that simple. So, you know, come
on come on
you know, no matter how he put it, he
already told you where you get your
information from. He said, "Seek ye out
of the the book of the Lord and read
it."
So, what's the reason
book of the Lord his word? His word will
not fail. That's why I said because it
came out of his mouth.
>> Yeah.
>> Matthew 5. Let's go to Matthew 5 quick.
Here's one of the places. Matthew 5 and
let's look at verse 17 and 18.
>> Matthew 5 and verse 17 and 18 says,
"Think not that I'm come to destroy the
law or the prophets. I am not come to
destroy, but to fulfill.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For verily I say unto you, till heaven
and earth pass, one jot or one tittle
shall in no wise pass from the law till
all be fulfilled."
>> None of the prophecy nothing that's
written in this book
everything got to be full everything
that Jesus came to do he had to fulfill
all of it.
From Genesis to Revelation all of it got
to be fulfilled. It has been will be and
going to be.
>> Mhm.
Yeah.
All right.
We hope that that answered your question
and as we move on to our next one.
>> Our next one, Kenyon Hayes
asks, "In Revelations 9 verse 11, are
the locust mentioned fallen angels or
demons? And is that pit a literal place
or spiritual at this time in history?
>> All right. And the And the scripture in
question, Revelation 9
>> 9
>> All right.
Go ahead, Brother James, when you get
there.
>> Okay. It says, "And they had a king over
them, which is the angel of the
bottomless pit, whose name in the Hebrew
tongue is Abaddon, but in the Greek
tongue hath his name Apollyon."
>> Means destroyer. Question, Deborah,
again.
>> All right.
Um
They want to know, I believe it should
not be Revelation 9, it should be a
Revelation 91.
>> Well, we don't have
>> There's no There's no Revelation 91. So,
her
uh question is, are the locust as
mentioned
fallen angels or demons? That's first.
And is that And is that pit a literal
place or spiritual at this time in
history?
>> Yeah, that's in Revelation 9, the third
verse, where it talk about the locust.
>> Start at verse 1.
>> Yeah, okay.
Revelation 9:1 says, "And the fifth
angel sounded, and I saw a star fall
from heaven unto the earth. And to him
was given the key of the bottomless pit.
And he opened the bottomless pit, and
there arose a smoke out of the pit, as
the smoke of a great furnace. And the
sun and the air were darkened by reason
of the smoke of the pit.
And there came out of the smoke locust
upon the earth, and unto them as were
given power as the scorpions of the
earth have power.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it was commanded them that they
should not hurt the grass of the earth,
neither any green thing, neither any
tree, but only those men which have not
the seal of God in their foreheads.
>> Now the locust is nothing but
>> Mhm.
>> but a
an army. Okay?
>> Yep.
>> And the king over
which is destroyer, is Satan the devil.
So when it says come out of the
bottomless pit, that don't mean that
they come up out of a literal bottomless
pit. It means that they're over there
and people see them and don't know what
they're looking at there.
>> Right.
>> And see and they had a king over them
which is Satan the devil. Go to
Revelation 13th chapter and start
reading at verse one.
>> Okay. It says Revelation 13 and 1 says
And I stood upon the sand of the sea and
I saw a beast rise up out of the sea
having seven heads and ten horns and
upon his horns ten crowns and upon his
heads the name of blasphemy.
And the beast which And the beast which
I saw was like a unto a leopard and his
feet were as the feet of a bear and his
mouth as the mouth of a lion and the
dragon gave him his power and his seat
and great authority.
And I saw Mhm.
>> And who who is the dragon? Satan the
devil. Isn't that right?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And he is
And he is the destroyer.
And he is the one he is the king of this
European Union
which is going to be
headed up the religious part
by the Catholic Church.
So all these locust that you see come
out of bottom of the pit, they're
nothing but the European army that's
going to be attacking the east. The west
west going to be attacking the east.
>> Mhm.
>> And they're going to be led by Satan the
devil.
Because he gave them his seat
hour and great authority.
>> Yeah.
>> From all of these the army of men.
And that's going to happen
uh
that's going to happen
during the time of the great
tribulation. That is scripture. That is
the call.
>> Mhm.
All right.
That was a good question and that was
some good light behind that. Let's uh
move on to our next question with a time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:34.
Lady Stringer asks
in the four winds of heaven
Daniel 8
8 verses 8 through 11
who is the horn that come out of the
four notable ones that cast down some of
a host of heaven stars to the ground and
stamped on them. Is this in 70 AD?
So, from the four winds of heaven
uh she goes to Daniel 8
8 through 11
verses 8 through 11 and she wants to
know who is the horn that come out of
the four notable ones that cast down
some of the host of heaven
stars to the ground and stamped on them
and did this in and is this in 70 AD?
>> All right, so that's uh
question got quite a bit in it, but
you're talking about the four winds of
heaven. And for our viewers out there,
this is the book The Four Winds of
Heaven. You can purchase and it helps
you a lot with history and the things to
come.
All right. Sorry, uh can't get a great
picture of it, but um that's the book.
And let's go to that Daniel 8.
That Daniel 8 there and um
pick it up at that verse 8 and
the guest caller
will begin to light on that one. Daniel
8 and 8.
>> Okay.
It says, "Therefore, the he-goat waxed
very great. And when he was strong, the
great horn was broken. And four it came
up four notable ones toward the four
winds of heaven.
And out of them came forth a little horn
which waxed exceeding great toward the
south and toward the east and toward the
pleasant land.
And it waxed great even to the host of
heaven. And it cast down some of the
host of the stars to the ground and
stamped upon it upon them.
Yea, he magnified himself even to the
prince of hosts and by him the daily
sacrifice was taken away and the place
of his sanctuary was cast down.
>> So, the whole thing is
that
uh when the horn is down, that's talking
about that's talking about the Greek
empire.
And the one that was broken
was Alexander the Great.
And what happened is Alexander the
Great, if you read the book, it would
tell you this.
Alexander the Great's generals got to
fighting and four of them ended up with
the Greek empire.
And in time past out of one of the
horns, that's the west horn
came another horn. That was the pope.
And he is going and he So, he came out
of cuz the western part of was Roman
Empire.
And he is going to stand up against
Jesus.
But he's going to be broken without
hands.
>> All right.
>> read
read the book it it explains all of
that.
>> Right.
And you can call the Israel God and you
can purchase your own copy of the four
winds of heaven.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next one. Lovely Cole asked,
"How do you know KJV is the right
Bible?"
>> All right. This is a question that we
get from time to time. Brother Julius, I
see you kind of shaking your head a
little bit. How do you know the King
James version is the book? And guest
caller, let us know also.
>> It is proven by history.
It is backed by history.
>> Yep.
>> It is backed by the word of God.
And it's a proven book.
>> Yeah.
Indeed. Guest caller, you want to like
to add?
>> Well, yeah. It's because and he he he
said it right.
This is history backed King James
version.
>> Yeah.
>> And you get the other version, you know,
it's like
other books. They got good stories in
them, but you cannot find no history
back them up. King James version let you
know from Cyrus left 40,000 people
uh go back to build his temple.
In his time, Cyrus the Persian king. You
can go to history and show that.
You know, what people don't know about
Jesus? That Jesus when he went back that
the reason Jesus was born in a manger
because why? The Caesar had wanted
everybody to go back to their native
country
so they could be taxed.
>> Yeah.
And you can go and find that in history.
Joseph and Mary back and they was taxed.
The Bible tell you that one angel
went out and killed 185,000
Assyrian soldiers.
At the At the wall of Jerusalem when
Hezekiah was king. You can go in there
>> That's right.
>> In one night 185 You can go in the
history and find it. And we got more
over and over and over just about
everything that happened,
you can find it. It's just like in 70 AD
when Titus took down
Jerusalem
and then and and uh
led them captive all over the uh all
over the Mediterranean. That is in
history. Even tell you the time it is
written that Jesus said that
he going cast the trench around
Jerusalem and keep everybody in.
They going to lay it even to the ground.
That is backed up in history in 70 AD.
Titus did that. And you can go on and on
and on. Like you talking about the
second chapter of Daniel, talking about
the 10 toes and 13 and
17 chapter of Revelation, talking about
the 10 horns, that's the European Union.
And it's but it's the 10th resurrection
of the Roman Empire, which is the fall
and rise
10 times. And the last time out of them
going come
the very one that's going to bring up
support the great tribulation.
All you got to do is go into history.
And it even tell you that these 10
European
Union nations
that makes up that second chapter of
Daniel's in Revelation 13 and and and
17, they have to try sign a treaty. It's
called a treatise of Rome.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Everything in that book is backed up by
history.
It's all that simple.
But if you don't read no history,
then you wouldn't know, would you?
That's all I have to say.
>> And we have a we have a lesson that is
called World History Told by the
Prophets. I mean,
man, just walk through from from from
beginning to end, the Bible is a history
book, but it's a book of prophecy.
>> And that's it.
>> Yeah.
Indeed.
All right. So,
we hope that uh
that light was shared on you as we
continue to move on to our next
question, sister.
>> Yes, next question. Mr. Incredible says,
"Randomly,
I hear conversation when I'm alone in
silence and have noticed at times the
things that I hear have come to
fruition.
Should I account these instances
to having the spirit of discernment?"
>> Well,
um
I know the Lord say, "Try the spirits
whether or not they are from God."
Open to the panel.
>> I don't have nothing to say about it.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
So,
all right. We're going to leave it there
and move on to our next question.
>> Uh next one. Splash asks, "How do you
explain to someone that it's okay to
celebrate your birthday,
but not other holidays like Christmas,
Easter, etc.
>> Well, the birthday,
um people always questioning that
because of Herod and Pharaoh did hung
somebody and killed somebody on their
birthday, but it doesn't say that you
can't celebrate your birthday in the in
the Bible. I don't
I haven't read that anywhere.
Um let's open up to the panel, but as
far as those other days they talking
about Easter and and what was the other
one, Deborah?
>> Uh Easter, Christmas, Easter,
etc.
>> All right, Easter dealing with Good
Friday and Christmas dealing with the
day that Christ was born.
Those are found to be fables. Open to
the panel.
>> Well, that's it. Bible Lord said he was
going to be in the grave 3 days and 3
nights.
>> That's right.
>> get 3 days.
So, they but they say he died Good
Friday and rose Easter Sunday morning.
You can't get 3 days and 3 nights
from Friday to Sunday.
>> Mhm.
>> Then they said that Jesus was born on
25th day of December.
Herod, which was king,
he didn't know when Jesus was born and
he was trying to kill it. That's why he
killed all the children from 2 years and
back from the time that he had inquired.
Verse in Jeremiah the 10th chapter tell
you
to find a Christmas tree. Said the
heathen do that, don't do that. But
there ain't nothing in the Bible
something wrong with that says something
wrong on your birthday.
You eat on your birthday. That mean you
should stop eating on your birthday?
You breathe on your birthday. What do
you think you should stop breathing
because you breathe on your birthday?
That's the most
But I'm not going to say it.
There ain't nothing in the Bible that's
against
the other bringing your birthday.
>> Nope.
Nope.
Yeah. Someone they gave
Methuselah a gift at 969 years. Nothing
was wrong with that, I don't think. All
right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> All right. Our next question.
Linda Stringers
asks, "Historical records show
early Roman Christians violently
persecuted
and forced people to convert all over
Africa and the world. Why do we call
ourselves Christians? Is there another
name for our faith?"
>> Listen.
I'm going to tell you something.
We are the original Christians.
>> Mhm.
>> Because since I'll get it
and Paul foolishness under you mean we
are going to
uh
uh reject the time? Go to 24th chapter
of St. Matthew and start reading.
>> Mhm.
>> Verse one.
>> Okay.
Matthew 24:1
says,
"And Jesus went out and departed from
the temple, and his disciples came to
him for to show him the buildings of the
temple.
And Jesus said unto them, 'See ye not
all these things? Verily I say unto you,
there shall not be left here one stone
upon another that shall not be thrown
down.'"
>> Go ahead.
>> "And as he sat upon the Mount of Olives,
the disciples came unto him privately,
saying, 'Tell us when shall these things
be? And what shall be the sign of thy
coming and of the end of the world?'"
>> Now, pay attention to what Jesus says
here. Go ahead.
>> And Jesus answered and said unto them,
"Take heed that no man deceive you.
For many shall come in For many shall
come in my name my name saying, 'I am
Christ' and shall deceive many."
>> Now, they going to come and they going
to come in the name of Jesus, but they
going to deceive many.
Jesus, as his custom was, he went into
the synagogue on the Sabbath day.
>> Right.
>> Jesus
That's That is the That's Jesus and the
original Christians teach that. The
original Christians teach you tell you
that Jesus going to come and he going to
sit on David's throne and he going to
rule the house of Israel forever and
from now he going to rule the whole
world from sea to sea.
These people that took his name
took the name Christian
and teaching it wrong said he going to
rapture you off to heaven.
So, now, what you going to do?
Throw the baby out with the bath water?
Jesus told you and warned you that many
going to come in his name saying that he
is Christ,
but they going to deceive many.
So, if you got a bad taste in your mouth
concerning Jesus, you going to have a
problem when you go to the wilderness
because the Lord said he going to cause
you to pass under the rod and bring you
into the bond of the covenant. And how
do you get into the bond of the
covenant? By being baptized in the name
of Jesus.
>> That's right.
>> Be careful lest you be end up in the
wilderness
because from all over the world
and get purged in the wilderness.
In other words, the Lord kill you right
there because you don't want to come
into the bond of the covenant. There be
one way to do it. You got to come under
the blood of Jesus just like the men
just like Israel was under the blood of
a
the lamb down in Egypt during Passover.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Saying in 1 Corinthians 5 and 7.
Purge out the old leaven become a new
lump because Jesus our Passover is
sacrificed for us.
So yeah, we Christian. We are the
original Christian. We not the Roman
Christian.
>> No.
Cornelius, can we go to that Acts 11,
Cornelius?
>> Yep, that's where I was going. Brother,
we are on the same mental wave there.
Acts 11 and where you want to pick it
up? That verse 25?
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right, brother. Yes, sir. And this
is uh
dealing with the word Christian, right?
>> named after some of these guys. Go
ahead.
>> Acts 12 and 25 I mean 11 and 25 says,
then departed Barnabas to Tarsus for to
seek Saul.
And when he had found him, he brought
him unto Antioch and it came to pass
that a whole year they assembled
themselves with the church and taught
much with the church.
And taught much people.
And the disciples were called Christians
first in Antioch.
>> Just to follow our Christ. That's what
we profess to be, the original followers
of Christ.
>> Mhm.
>> That's it. You getting mixed up with
these people being in Rome and you want
to spit on the name of Christ, of Jesus.
I'mma tell you, you treading on
dangerous ground.
>> Yeah.
>> I have to say.
>> Yep, repent of that and turn and serve
God. All right.
Sister Deborah, time check with our next
question.
>> Yes, time is 8:50. Next question, Sister
Prudent asks, how are we to observe the
new moon each month?
>> All right, the new moon each month open
to the panel.
>> There ain't nothing in there so you
spooked up there, is it? You just know
when you use it this
you know when the month start.
>> That's it.
>> But the Lord didn't command you to do
nothing with the new moon.
If you want to know what the Lord
commanded you to observe, it's written
in the 23rd chapter of Leviticus.
>> That's right.
>> We have people that observe the new
moon. Be careful lest you find yourself
worshipping
the
orders of heaven.
>> Yeah.
That's right. All right.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Our next question,
Jesse 4K asks, "When Jesus rose from the
dead, it proves
our body is the soul. He couldn't have
been able to put the hand
in his side, right?
I just wanted to clarify that this is
true
or false."
So again, when Jesus rose from the dead,
it proved
it proves our body
is the soul. He couldn't have been able
to put his right hand
I
uh
his right hand. I I just wanted to
clarify that that's true or false.
>> All right.
Don't prove anything. Only thing that
proves that he was the one that was dead
and he rose again. And once he rose, he
was no longer
a
living soul. He was a living spirit. So
the book say, you know, that would put
to death uh uh uh
in the flesh and quickened in the
spirit. You understand? The first man
Adam
a a living soul.
Will somebody go to uh uh
Genesis
2:7 and read that.
>> All right.
>> And then I'm going to go someplace and
show you what a soul is also.
>> Genesis 2:7
says, "And the Lord God formed man of
the dust of the ground and breathed into
his nostrils the breath of life, and man
became a living soul."
>> And that's it. And And in 1 Corinthians
15, it will tell you the first man Adam
was made a living soul.
Go read it.
In 1 Corinthians 15
>> It It say It says, "1 Corinthians 15:45
It says, 'And so it is written, The
first man Adam was made a living soul,
the last Adam was made a quickening
spirit.'"
>> Keep reading and see what that last Adam
was.
>> "How be it, that was not first which is
spiritual, but that which is natural,
and afterward that which is spiritual.
The first man is of the earth earthy.
The second man is the Lord from heaven."
>> Do not
put in a hand and and and ways put the
spirit in prove that he was a soul. At
that point he was no longer a soul.
But the Lord can show up under any uh uh
uh any form that he want. Just like he
showed up with Abraham with two angels.
They all looked like three men, but they
was going down to destroy Sodom and
Gomorrah.
>> Mhm.
>> So no, that don't prove he was a soul.
He wasn't a soul at that but a living
spirit.
Only thing that proved that he was the
one
he he did that to let them know to prove
that he was the one that died on the
cross and was the one that they stuck in
the side with a spear.
But he was no longer a soul. He was a
quickening spirit.
Spirits can't die.
Souls can.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
>> On your own, you can go to Leviticus the
fifth chapter and it'll tell you the
soul got everything that I got. That we
all have. Leviticus 5, James. Real
quick.
>> Okay.
>> Soul is just another word for body.
You got the Bible?
>> It says, "And if a soul sin and hear the
voice of swearing and is a witness,
whether he have seen or known of it, if
he do not utter it, then he shall bear
his iniquity."
>> Now, look at look at all these
characteristics of a soul. It a soul can
sin, a soul got ears, a soul got lips to
speak. And verse two.
>> Or if a soul toucheth any unclean
>> A soul can touch.
Verse four.
>> Or if a soul swear
pronouncing with his lips to do evil or
to do good.
>> The soul got everything that we have
because we are all living souls while we
have breath in us.
Take away the breath, we are dead souls.
Just the Bible.
>> All right.
We're going to leave it there, sister
Deborah, as we know time is a ticking.
Our next question.
>> Yes, Valencia asks, "Can you explain
Ezekiel 17
verses 3 through 6?"
>> Ezekiel 17?
>> Yes.
>> Verses 3 through
>> 3 through 6.
>> All right, let's go there, brother.
You ready? Ezekiel 17
and
let's pick it up at that verse three
and read it through that um
six. Go right ahead, brother.
>> Ezekiel 17 and 3 says, "And say, thus
saith the Lord God, a great eagle with
great wings long winded, full of
feathers which have divers colors, came
unto Lebanon and took the highest branch
of the cedar.
He cropped off the top of his young
twigs and carried it into a land of
traffic. He set it in a city of
merchants. He took also of the seed of
the land and planted it in a fruitful
field. He placed it by great waters and
set it as a willow tree. And it grew and
became a spreading vine of low stature
whose branches turned toward him and the
roots thereof were under him. So it
became a vine and brought forth branches
and shot forth sprigs."
>> Mhm.
Skip down to verse 11.
>> Moreover, the word of the Lord came unto
me saying, "Say now to the rebellious
house, know ye not what these things
mean? Tell them, behold, the king of
Babylon is come to Jerusalem and have
taken the king thereof and the princes
thereof and led them with him to
Babylon.
>> Keep reading.
>> And has taken of the king's seed and
made a covenant with him and have taken
an oath of him. He has also taken the
mighty of the land
that the king
>> This is where Nebuchadnezzar came and
took down Jerusalem. Yeah,
Nebuchadnezzar.
Yeah.
But read about why and the other
I rebelled by by sending for Egypt. That
was the other eagle.
>> Mhm.
>> That was verse seven. Yes, call it
something like verse seven.
>> Okay.
There was also another great eagle with
great wings and many feathers. And
behold, this vine did bend her roots
toward him and shot forth her branches
toward him that he might water it by the
furrows of her plantation.
>> Okay, all it is is that Nebuchadnezzar,
the Babylonian,
actually
that was a this deal was broken by God.
God said cuz
uh Zedekiah broke his his uh covenant.
He made He He made a deal with Zedekiah
and set him up as king.
All he had to do was pay tribute to
Babylon.
And the nation of Israel Judah would
still be there cuz the Lord had fixed
it. What did Zedekiah do? He sent for
and hi- hired the armies of Egypt.
Yeah. Of of the
of Egypt?
And Nebuchadnezzar and they rebelled
against Nebuchadnezzar. So, what
happened to him?
Nebuchadnezzar come in
and took Zedekiah, destroyed Jerusalem,
burnt down the temple,
and the ones that he didn't kill, he
took to Babylon as captive.
And that was the end
of
new deal.
So, the two eagles is one is Babylon and
the other one is Egypt.
>> Yeah.
>> And the and the
plant that was a uh
uh uh
the twig that was planted was Zedekiah.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yep.
>> All right.
>> Read the whole chapter.
On your own home.
>> Yeah, read.
As you read the whole chapter, it will
explain itself.
>> Yeah.
That's it. All right. Sister Deborah,
time check.
>> It is 9:00.
>> All right. Well, if it is 9:00, we have
ran out of time. We want to thank you
all from all around the world who sent
in those great questions. We took joy in
sharing some light on them. But, we like
to say that if you submitted a question
and we didn't get to it, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take your
question, put it on rotation, and we
would deal with that at our next Q&A
session. But, thank you all for joining
us, and we say until we all come
together again, please be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
James closes us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever.
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.